the Supreme Court will hear the crucial
AGR case today on the previous date of
hearing in June the top Court had agreed
to consider deferred payment plans by
telecom companies subject to submission
of some guarantee to ensure that they
abide by the payment plan also they were
asked to submit their revenue and tax
details from the past one decade before
the top qut for consideration the
consideration may take place today the
do was asked to file replies to the
affidavits and other details which were
filed by different telecom companies the
do earlier itself had agreed to consider
deferred payment plans while the telecom
companies had maintained that many of
them will fold up if at all they are
asked to pay the entire amount upfront
however the top code had observed that
telecom is the only sector which was
making money throughout the pandemic and
hence they must deposit some amount
since the government needs money during
the pandemic on the 11th of June the top
Court had agreed to consider staggered
AGR payments subject to some security
and do was asked to file replies to
affidavits filed by telecom companies
Vodafone idea till now has paid
7,854 crores out of the total AGR dues
of over 588,000 crores while paral has
paid over 18,000 crores out of the total
AGR dues of
43,98221 since they had posted losses of
over 1 lakh crores in several quarters
uh they had also said that they'll fold
up if at all they are asked to pay
upfront and the only way to stay a float
is payment over a period of 20 years
something which is going to be decided
by the top Court vfa had also opposed
that their independent directors should
be asked to pay uh to pay guarantees or
to pay dues of over 50,000 crores they
had refused to do the same on uh the
17th of March this year the top Court
had scrapped self assessment of AGR dues
by telecom companies and had asked them
to abide by the 24th October verdict
from last year when the top Court had
upheld Do's definition of adjusted gross
revenue and the total demand for over
92,000 crores was upheld adjusted gross
revenue is the basis of collection of
levies from telecom companies by the do
they were asked to pay all dues by the
23rd of January uh to the do which they
had refused to pay at one instant they
had said that they will abide by the top
court order but they need time since it
is a huge amount and they sought a large
amount of time uh to pay such kind of
dues it remains to be seen whether the
top Cod is going to give them any
further time or whether a deferred
payment plan would be accepted uh and uh
what kind of guarantee would be given
from the side of telecom companies in
order to put forth their case before The
Supreme Court